Inventory of the François Mitterrand speeches and writings
Hoover Institution Archives
François Mitterrand speeches and writings
1981-1986
81091
Hoover Institution Archives
7 manuscript boxes (2.8 linear feet)
Transcripts of speeches, statements, press conferences, and interviews, relating to French domestic and foreign policy.
Mitterrand, François, 1916-1996
Access
Collection is open for research. The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1981.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical/Historical Note
The French politician and statesman François Mitterrand (1916-1996) was elected president of France in 1981, serving until his retirement in 1995.
Scope and Content of Collection
Transcripts of speeches, statements, press conferences, and interviews, relating to French domestic and foreign policy.
France--Foreign relations--1945-; France--Politics and government--1981-; Statesmen--France.
- Interviews, June 1981 - January 1983
  - June 1981 - April 1982 (Box-folder 1: 6)
  - May 1982 - January 1983 (Box-folder 2: 7)
- Speeches and Declarations, May 1981 - March 1986
  - May 1981 - April 1982 (Box-folder 1: 7-8)
  - April 1982 - September 1982 (Box-folder 2: 8-10)
  - September 1982 - June 1983 (Box-folder 3: 1-5)
  - July 1983 - March 1984 (Box-folder 4: 1-5)
  - April - December 1984 (Box-folder 5: 1-5)
  - January - May 1985 (Box-folder 6: 1-2)
  - June 1985 - March 1986 (Box-folder 7: 1-5)
- Geographic files, 1981 - 1982
  - Afrique, November 1981 - December 1981 (Box-folder 1: 3)
  - Allemagne, October 1982 (Box-folder 2: 2)
  - Burundi, October 1982 (Box-folder 2: 3)
  - Canada, July 1981 (Box-folder 1: 5)
  - Etats-Unis, October 1981 - March 1982 (Box-folder 1: 1)
  - Mexique, October 1981 (Box-folder 1: 4)
  - Portugal, December 1981 (Box-folder 1: 2)
  - Strasbourg, September 1982 (Box-folder 2: 1)
  - Rwanda, October 1982 (Box-folder 2: 4)
  - Zaire, October 1982 (Box-folder 2: 5)